now that we know that we need the
reorder buffer to hold the results of
instructions until they're ready to
finish in program order let's see what
it looks like the reorder buffer is a
table of entries in each entry we keep
at least three
Fields one says what the value produced
by the instruction is this is the value
that we are not writing to the register
when the instruction finishes it will
now write its value to the reorder
buffer when it broadcasts
we need a bit here to tell us whether we
actually have a valid value here or not
because we will give a reorder buffer
entry to the instruction before it
actually writes the result and finally
in the end we have to write this value
to an actual register and for that we
need to know when we do such a write
when we move this value from the reorder
buffer to a register what register are
we going to write
to this is a reorder buffer that can
hold up to eight instructions
and we keep instructions in the reorder
buffer in program order so we need two
pointers one pointer tells us when we
issue the next instruction where does it
go another one tells us when we finally
complete in program order the next
instruction which instruction is it
going to be so in this particular
reorder buffer the instructions that are
actually valid
are starting from the oldest
one to the newest one this the even
newer instructions are going to be added
here and the oldest one will complete
from here so these five instructions are
actually in program order in the reorder
buffer